A Guide to the Charles Burton Fahs papers FA099
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional papers, 1933-1973, 1980-1988; 2
  - Miami University - Memoranda, 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Miami University - A Proposal for the Establishment and Funding of the Center for International Business, 1974 May (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Grolier, Inc., 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Japanese Literary Fellowship Program - Tribute Book (Box 14, Folder 221)
  - Embassy of the United States, Tokyo, Japan - Book of Tributes and Farewell Messages (Box 14, Folder 222)
  - Office of Strategic Services - Dog Tags, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 223)
- Professional correspondence, 1933-1990; 3
  Letters in this series are separate from correspondence found in Series 2 which is affiliated with a specific job or employer. Letters were received from a wide range of people, including strangers, acquaintances, and friends and professional colleagues from all stages of Burton’s life. Numerous Rockefeller Foundation colleagues, U.S. diplomats, and Asian scholars and politicians corresponded with Burton. Letters can be quite brief and perfunctory, or they can be lengthy and full of warmth and collegiality.
  Correspondence dating after 1980 was received by Jamie Ross Fahs, who incorporated her letters into her husband’s files. Generally these letters include information about Burton’s relationship with the correspondent.
  Important correspondents in this series include: John Kenneth Emmerson, Naomi Fukuda, Clifton Forster, Richard H. Minear, Virginia Moreno, Shigeharu Matsumoto, John E. Reinhardt, Edwin O. Reischauer, Flora Rhind, Dean Rusk, Shio Sakanishi, Margaret Shedd, and David H. Stevens.
  Files in this series are arranged alphabetically, and individually named folders are filed before the specific alphabetical range.
  - American Political Science Association, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Asia Society, 1965-1980 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1969-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - A (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - B (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - C (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - D (Box 7, Folder 112)
  - E (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Far Eastern Association, 1946-1953 (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - F (Box 7, Folder 115)
  - Grolier, Inc., 1969-1979 (Box 7, Folder 116)
  - G (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - Masunori Hiratsuka, 1968-1975 (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - H (Box 7, Folder 119)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1936-1951 (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - The International House of Japan, Inc., 1955-1990 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - I (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - The Japan P.E.N. Club - International Conference on Japanese Studies, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - J (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Seiji Kaya, 1968-1975 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Kokugakuin University, 1968-1979 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - K (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - L (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Miami University Library, 1971, 1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Midwest Japan Seminar, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Richard H. Minear, 1972, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Ma-Me (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Mi-Mu (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - New World Books, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Northwestern University Archives, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - N (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Ohio Asianists, undated (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Operations Research Office, Johns Hopkins University, 1949-1955 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - Oxford Men's Club, 1964, 1974-1979 (Box 9, Folder 139)
  - O (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1964-1979 (Box 9, Folder 141)
  - P (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Q (Box 9, Folder 143)
  - R (Box 9, Folder 144)
  - Shio Sakanishi, 1967-1976 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Sa-Sh (Box 9, Folder 146)
  - Si-Sw (Box 9, Folder 147)
  - T (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization - Meeting of Ministers of Education of Asian Member States, 1962, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 149)
  - United States-Japan Trade Council, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - Momoko Urakami, 1967-1975 (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - U (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - V (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - Richard R. Willis, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 154)
    Restricted from scholarly access
  - W (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - Y-Z (Box 10, Folder 156)
- Manuscripts, Publications and Speeches, 1929-1979; 4
  The Manuscripts section includes any unpublished writings or writings which were unable to be verified as published or presented in a speech. Publications include monographs, book reviews, articles for academic journals, and articles for the popular press. Speeches include speeches, papers given at conferences, informal presentations, and radio presentations. The topics of Fahs’s writings include current events, customs and traditions of other countries, international studies, education, politics, economics, foreign policy, religion, international travel, cultural exchange, Japan, and study abroad.
  For a complete listing of Fahs’s writings and background information on certain projects, researchers should see Series 1, Box 1, Folder 6, Biography – Draft of Chapter or Appendix “The Written and Spoken Word of Charles Burton Fahs,” undated.
  Files in this series are arranged alphabetically by type (Manuscript, Publication, or Speech) and thereunder chronologically. Writings which were described as articles but had no publication information were filed with Manuscripts. Publications are filed by the date they were written, rather than when they were published. Published remarks of talks were filed with Speeches.
  - Manuscripts - "Whither Tariffs?", 1932, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Manuscripts - Institute of Pacific Relations Conference, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - Manuscripts - Essays Completed While Studying Abroad, 1934-1936 (Box 10, Folder 159)
  - Manuscripts - "Foreign Study", c. 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 160)
  - Manuscripts - Department of State, c. 1945 (Box 10, Folder 161)
  - Manuscripts - "Beyond Okinawa - Korea", c. 1969 (Box 10, Folder 162)
  - Manuscripts - Oxford Men's Club, 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 163)
  - Publications - The Intercollegian, 1927, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Publications - Articles for International Periodicals, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Publications - Abstracts of Articles Appearing in Current Japanese Periodicals, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Publications - Book Reviews, 1937-1941, undated (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Publications - Claremont Oriental Studies, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 168)
  - Publications - "Political Groups in the Japanese House of Peers", 1940 (Box 10, Folder 169)
  - Publications - Monographs, 1931-1940 (Box 10, Folder 170)
  - Publications - Reviews of Charles Burton Fahs' Books, 1938-1942 (Box 10, Folder 171)
  - Publications - "American Education and the Far East" by Dorothy Borg, John King Fairbank, Charles Burton Fahs, and Howard E. Wilson, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - Publications - "American Education and the Far East" by Dorothy Borg, John King Fairbank, Charles Burton Fahs, and Howard E. Wilson, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Publications - "How Should a Professor Look at His University Library?", 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Publications - "Political Self-Education", 1971 May (Box 10, Folder 175)
  - Publications - "Japan - East or West?", 1977 August (Box 10, Folder 176)
  - Publications - "Hopes for Japan's Cultural Relations", 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 177)
  - Speeches - Institute for Oriental Students, c. 1930-1936 (Box 11, Folder 178)
  - Speeches - "What Can Be Achieved by an American Boycott?", 1932 February 10 (Box 11, Folder 179)
  - Speeches - "New Years in Japan", 1937 January (Box 11, Folder 180)
  - Speeches - "Recent Japanese Politics: An Interpretation", 1937 February 27 (Box 11, Folder 181)
  - Speeches - Presentation at The Church in Radburn on Laymen's Day, 1952 October 19 (Box 11, Folder 182)
  - Speeches - Presentations at the Tenth Annual Meeting of the Social Science Research Conference of the Pacific Coast, 1940 March 21-23 (Box 11, Folder 183)
  - Speeches - "The Problems in American-Japanese Cultural Exchange", 1962 February 23 (Box 11, Folder 184)
  - Speeches - "Japan's Democracy: My Reflections and Suggestions", 1966 November 15 (Box 11, Folder 185)
  - Speeches - "Study Abroad: Suggested Goals for State Universities", 1968 October 4 (Box 11, Folder 186)
  - Speeches - "Cultural Exchange: The First Step to Cooperation", 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 187)
- Awards and Citations, 1929, 1934-1935, 1946, 1960-1967, and 1978-1979; 5
  Fahs received various academic awards, including induction into Phi Beta Kappa at the end of his undergraduate career, the first honorary degree ever conferred by Kokugakuin University in Japan (1964), and an honorary doctorate from Miami University in 1979. Fahs also received several government service awards, most notably the Medal of Freedom in 1946. He also received various awards from foreign governments and foreign organizations over the course of his life, ranging from more lighthearted awards for activities like archery to the highly prestigious Japan Foundation Award in 1979.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Academic Awards, 1929, 1964-1973 (Box 11, Folder 189)
  - Awards from Foreign Countries and Foreign Organizations, 1934-1935, 1960-1967, undated (Box 11, Folder 190)
  - Government Service Awards, 1946, 1967, undated (Box 11, Folder 191)
  - Miami University - Honorary Degree, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 192)
  - Miami University - Honorary Degree - Supporting Materials, 1946-1975 (Box 11, Folder 193)
  - Japan Foundation Award, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 194)
  - Japan Foundation Award - Congratulatory Letters, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 195)
  - Japan Foundation Award - Gift, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 196)
  - Japan Foundation Award - Publicity, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 197)
  - Academic Awards - Miami University Certificate of Service, 1973 June 15 (Box 13, Folder 219)
  - Awards from Foreign Countries and Foreign Organizations - Japanese Archery Awards (Box 13, Folder 220)
  - Awards from Foreign Countries and Foreign Organizations - Certificate for the Shodan Ranking in Go, 1964 September 16 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Awards from Foreign Countries and Foreign Organizations - Certificate for Honorary Membership of the Chin-Tan Society, 1965 November 8 (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Academic Awards - Honorary Doctorate, Kokugakuin University, Japan, 1964 November 4 (Box 17, Folder 226)
  - Japan Award Foundation, 1979 October 2 (Box 17, Folder 227)
  - Awards from Foreign Countries and Foreign Organizations - Order of the Sacred Treasure, Third Class, 1960 September 8 (Folder 7)
    Separated Materials
    Material separated to RAC Map Cases for flat storage.
- Photographs, 1929, 1946-1979; 6
  The majority of photographs are from the Rockefeller Foundation and Embassy years (1947-1966). There are very few candid, personal, or family photographs. The majority of the photographs are black and white; there are a few color photographs. Most of the photographs are captioned; the captioning was often added to by Jamie Ross Fahs, and occasionally the dates are incorrect.
  The earliest photographs in this series are Burton’s snapshots from his travels through Europe in 1929 and 1930. Photographs taken on Rockefeller Foundation trips are significant, as they often document Burton’s visits with artists, writers, and academics of other countries. Photographs taken during the Embassy years document Burton in meetings and at conferences, as well the Fahs' taking part in official ceremonies and outings. Photographs from various awards ceremonies often document Fahs with other important academics, dignitaries, and politicians. Rare family images are the portrait of Burton, Jamie, Jimmie, and Barbara at the Medal of Freedom award ceremony in 1946, one photograph of the family at Jim’s wedding, and one photograph from Barbara’s wedding to Nicholas Charles.
  The photographs are arranged chronologically, and the passport photos are filed first. In the run of Rockefeller Foundation folders, the two general folders are filed first, followed by folders for specific trips. Undated photos are filed after the Japan Foundation Award folder. Photographs removed from the paper-based collection are filed at the end of the series.
  - Passport Photographs, 1952, c. 1973 (Box 12, Folder 198)
  - Medal of Freedom Award Ceremony, 1946 August 15 (Box 12, Folder 199)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 200)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1954-1961 (Box 12, Folder 200A)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Trip to the Far East, 1953 April 6-June 6 (Box 12, Folder 201)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Trip to the Far East, 1958 April (Box 12, Folder 201A)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Trip to Southeast Asia - Philippines, 1958 September (Box 12, Folder 202)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Trip to the Far East, 1959 April (Box 12, Folder 203)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Trip to Japan, 1960 April (Box 12, Folder 204)
  - Order of the Sacred Treasure - Award Ceremony, 1960 September 8 (Box 12, Folder 205)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Trip to Japan, 1961 April (Box 12, Folder 206)
  - Cultural Conference, Tokyo, Japan, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - Embassy of the United States, Tokyo, Japan, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Embassy of the United States, Tokyo, Japan, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 209)
  - Kokugakuin University - Honorary Degree - Ceremony, 1964 November 4 (Box 12, Folder 210)
  - Embassy of the United States, Tokyo, Japan, 1964-1966 (Box 12, Folder 211)
  - Academic Career, 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Japan Foundation Award - Award Ceremony, 1979 October 2 (Box 12, Folder 213)
  - Undated Photographs (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - Photographs Removed from Series 1, 1929, 1964-1967 (Box 12, Folder 215)
    Photographic materials separated from the body of the Charles Burton Fahs papers.
  - Photographs Removed from Series 2, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 216)
  - Photographs Removed from Series 3, 1950-1972 (Box 12, Folder 217)
  - Photographs Removed from Series 5, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 217A)